you
Hi 我是 Feel Tennis 的Thomas
发球时最网球中最复杂的一击
因此特别难掌握
你如果想掌握正规的先进发球技术
意味着使用大陆式握拍
用上旋 切削 平击 的方式击球
为了构建先进的有技术含量的发球必须遵循适当的连续击球动作
下面的视频是网球发球基础概述
我会展循序渐进展示
7个日常使用的动作
也是向拜访我的网球玩家演示发球时展示的
大多时候我没有必要深究发球细节
但我会确保这些基础技术到位才会开始发球
第一步是正确的站姿
对于右手持拍者
让你的左脚指向右网柱
右脚平行于底线
右脚脚尖对齐左脚脚跟
这是基本站姿
但是可以根据发球的方向稍作调整
我推荐的做法是
当你开始构建你的发球技术
将球发向Edward角
讲到击球部分时 我会详细解释那么做的必要性
第二步是正确的握拍
如果想要打出带上旋或侧旋的平击球
必须要大陆式握拍
找出大陆式握拍的方式之一是
将持拍手放到拍上
左手食指放在
挨着大拇指的虎口
食指指向拍子的上左棱线
第三步是击球部分
是发球技术中最重要的一环
通常我会在引拍之前先做这部分
因为你会意识到击球动作正确的话 引拍也会自然到位
让你做到想做的
因此击球部分比引拍动作重要得多
most common mistakes that players make
even when they hold the Continental grip
and even if they have a proper stance is
that once they begin their serve they
start to orient very quickly towards the
court and then they swing towards the
target with their whole arm I know
that's the most natural for us but
that's not how an advanced serve works
so their usual serve looks something
like this so they turn towards the
target they go very strongly from their
shoulder and they usually finish on
their left and so in order for me to
correct these players I use a very
simple system which teaches them that
the serve has instead of one swing path
towards the target it actually has two
swing pass so the first swing path is
roughly at a 45 degree angle and then
the second one is perpendicular to the
net and this is how we simulate the
proper movement of the arm so when we
toss the ball for the normal usual serve
for the flat serve or maybe for this
slice serve the ball is somewhere in
front of us and a little bit to the
right and so our first swing path
towards the ball is with the edge so
we're swinging towards the ball with the
edge at the 45 degree angle and then we
can imagine that once the racket reaches
the ball and the strings are pointing
towards the target we switch our
movements to this one and so it's not
just one continuous movement but we
imagine that our arm moves this way at a
roughly 45 degree angle and then we
pronate towards the target at least we
can simplify and make this movement of
pronation it's a little bit more complex
movement but for now we'll just call it
the pronation so our service
Swink towards the ball and then
pronation and it looks something like
this in this third part
and so this is the main difference
between a very simple serve towards the
target and a more advanced serve where
our arm makes to swing pass of course
later we do it in a very smooth manner
and these two swing paths seem to merge
together but if you're serving correctly
or pretty aware that you are swinging
like in two directions towards the ball
because we are now breaking down the
serve into smaller parts so that they
are easier to learn we are unfortunately
also breaking down the natural flow of
the body and so as this is especially
obvious in this part where we're trying
to learn the proper swing path towards
the ball and one way we can solve this
problem is that when we're starting to
serve from this position we don't start
from a static position but we do a
little bounce as I like to call it
so we you can bounce the racquet a
little bit like this and then go from
this bounce into swing path number one
and then swing path number two so the
whole exercise looks something like this
I just want to loosen up a little bit
and then I do one two on the ball
here's one more
a little bit more advanced way of doing
this exercise is to actually try and do
the bounce one more bounce
after you have tossed the ball so it
looks something like this so I start
with my racket a little bit higher so
that I feel that I have some space to
drop the racket or to bounce it off
something so my hand my arm is very
loose so I start from here I toss the
ball first and after I toss the ball I
release I let go of the racket I feel
this bounce and then I'm doing one two
you
now this has shown to be very effective
for learning the proper drop of the surf
later when you're going to put the whole
surf together if you've done a few of
these bosses it will just happen very
naturally that you're doing the proper
drop in the surf step four is the
backswing with the toss I won't go into
too many details about the toss so for
now just this so place the ball right in
the middle of your palm and then just
hold it with your thumb and you're
leaving some space on the tips of your
fingers where you're going to place your
racket so also know that you're tossing
with a straight arm so for those of you
who would like to know more details
about the toss you can take a look into
my surf course here's how we're going to
work on the backswing you're going to
swing both arms simultaneously like a
pendulum and let them go up and down
simultaneously and eventually you're
going to end up in this position which
we're going to call the trophy position
I personally don't like to teach the
completely vertical racquet in the
trophy position and that's for two
reasons number one oftentimes when
players end up in this position and
they're about to initiate their serve
the racket really likes to fall into
this direction and open up the palm of
the hand which we call the waiters tray
serve and that's really bad for the
acceleration so it really doesn't give
you a good acceleration on the ball and
it prevents good topspin and good slice
so if you're in this position many times
the racket wants to go this way and the
other reason is if I show from this
angle when players toss the ball and
they're in this position like very
vertical racket they feel they have a
long way to go to complete their draw up
their backswing and then coming up to
the ball so what happens oftentimes is
they shorten it they make it quite
shallow and they serve like this so the
drop is way too shallow because they
feel they don't have enough time so what
I prefer to do is I prefer to teach this
trophy position where the racquet is
close to the head
so one way you can check that is that
you do your backswing and then you just
tap the back of your head with the
bottom edge of the racket so you're
hearing of course there must be some
space between the racket and the head
but in order for you to know whether in
the right place you just move the racket
this way and you check ok I'm in the
right place then you move it back so
this is the backs the backswing sequence
you're going to toss the ball and catch
it back again and then check if your
racket is in the right place now this
exercise is also very good to work on
your toes so you don't need any specific
exercises for the toss unless you're
having some really big problems because
this exercise is automatically teaching
you how to move your arm properly and
where to toss the ball because the ball
must fall right back into your hand so
here's the backswing sequence again you
want to toss the ball and they'll just
check with your racket if you're
somewhere close to your head step 5 is
putting everything together what you've
learned so far so we're going to put
together the backswing and the hitting
part and so we're going to break down
the serving into two parts the first
part is doing the backswing and catching
the ball
finding your trophy position and then
you're going to remain in your trophy
position you will initiate the toss
again and then you're going to do the 1
2 exercise so the bouncing want to
exercise which you've already done
before so the whole sequence looks like
this we're doing the back swing we're
catching the ball we're checking if
you're in the right position then we're
going to toss again and do once to again
so that's why we can still leave the
balls because they give us proper
guidance of the to sweep paths so here's
one more example part 1 I'm in the right
place I can feel and I start again and
I'm doing 1 2 so hopefully you can see
that this is starting to resemble the
proper serve so here we go again
the first part I check I do the bounce
and one two now we're almost ready to
put the whole surf together but before
we do that I'd like you to work on one
exercise that actually produces the most
power in the surf and for that you have
to do two things simultaneously so what
needs to happen is that when your racket
is starting to drop your body must start
to turn or in other words we initiate
the rotation of the body to our hips and
then continue with our shoulders so some
words that you might hear that they
relate to these are drive with your hip
forward or rotate your hip or rotate
your shoulders but it's very important
that this happens at the same time so
your racket drop and your body rotation
must happen in the same time I know we
like to have things step by step or in
sequence that are very clear but in this
case we cannot separate the drop from
the body rotation which is again one of
very common mistakes that I see with
players so they're completing the drop
they want to work in sequence in their
mind they have a certain sequence so now
I complete the drop okay now I'm doing
the serve but in order for yourself to
produce very effortless power you must
simultaneously drop the racket and start
driving your hip forward or start
rotating so you're actually doing this
exercise separately and I'll show from
this angle and first you're doing
without the ball and you're just trying
to feel that as soon as you start
dropping the racket you are start
driving your hip forward so in this case
you can exaggerate a little bit and
rotate your body a little bit more then
you will actually do when you're serving
but this gives you the right feel
because when you do it right you will
just feel that your racket naturally
accelerate or you might feel that your
arm is like thrown out from this
position so again is the key is that as
you're starting your drop you're
loosening up your arm and you're
starting to turn
your body so from this angle it looks
something like this
looks something like this and then you
can continue or from this angle it looks
something like this
you
and here's the power move from the side
angle so first without the ball you're
starting from your trophy position and
you're trying to feel okay as soon as I
drop my racket I drive forward my hip
and so you go like this and then you can
just complete your serve so in this case
because we want to really feel what's
going on we can exaggerate a little bit
and you can turn really forward like
facing the court but keep in mind that
when you're doing a proper serve we
don't face the court until we finish
hitting the ball so when we're hitting
the ball we are at roughly 45 degree
angle with the body we are not facing
the court yet and only then after we
have completed the contact with the ball
and we've completed the swing path
number two we can start turning towards
the court but in this case because you
really want to feel the effects of
simultaneously dropping the racket and
turning your body just feel free to
really turn towards the court really
drive your hip forward really rotate and
then let the racket go so again without
the ball it's like this and then you can
also hit some balls where you start
trying to feel the effects of the power
move
step seven is of course putting
everything together so what you can do
first is you can do one serving two
parts where you really feel it how the
serve works and then just take a leap of
faith and do the whole serve together
and see how it feels so with some
repetition and practice and I also
recommend that you record yourself
you're going to start to see that your
serve starts to look like a proper
advance serve now one more thought about
the follow-through I've been sticking
with this follow through for quite a
while because as I mentioned before one
of the most common mistakes that players
make is to use their arm a lot rather
than this move to hit the ball and they
oftentimes end up on the left side so
yes we do end up on the left side so let
me show from this angle so when we
complete our serve we do end up on the
left side but we can do it the wrong way
and the right way the wrong way is that
as we're about to hit the ball we are
forcefully moving the racket to the left
side with our shoulder but that's not
how the racket gets to the left side it
actually gets to the left side because
we're hitting the servant we're swinging
out towards the right side we're
pronating and then we're allowing the
body to uncoil or to unwind and our arm
will naturally swing to the left
so basically we're swinging arm towards
more to the right side and then we are
coming back with the body towards the
middle we're loosening up and that's how
the arm comes to the left side so keep
that in mind when you're working on the
serve when you're completing the whole
serve that you feel that the racket
actually comes to the left side as you
loosen up and not because you're
actually swinging very forcefully from
your shoulder towards the left side
so try to see this in my serve where I
will stick for a while on the right side
so I'll complete the serve on the right
side and I will just gently allow my
body to come back to the straight
position that my shoulders become more
level and then you will see that the
racket naturally swings to my left side
so in my serve this is a little bit
hidden when you see everything together
but now that you know what you're
looking for you will understand how the
racket comes to the left side of the
body now there's one more part that you
have to work on as you're improving your
serve namely you have to work on the
flow on the fluidity of the serve right
now we have broken down the serve into
many parts so that they're easier to
learn but in the process we have also
broken down the natural movement of the
body we have broken down the flow the
fluidity and so we have to keep putting
it back together and so one of the best
tools you can use is the serve master by
Lisa Dotson and you just simply swing it
in a continuous motion like this so you
can do follow-through on the left side
but you can also do follow-through on
the right side and if you go over to the
total serve com you will find very
detailed instructions on how you can
start working with the serve master what
are the right progressions but the key
point is that you want to re-establish
the fluidity of your body the fluidity
of your motion because we have been
breaking it down and especially when you
work on yourself repeatedly and there
are certain parts of your serve that are
not really good
perhaps the heating part so again you'll
be breaking down your serve into a
smaller part and it might become very
stiff very mechanical and so your final
goal is to polish these little breaks in
your serve so that everything is
smoothly flowing and so one of the best
ways is the total serve using the total
serve you can of course use also the
ball on the string that I've
demonstrated one time before or the
classical trick balls in the sock but
you can also use your racket which you
hold with three fingers and again you
just make it go in a very similar manner
so in a very continuous smooth motion
that never stops so that means that you
reestablish the flow because flow means
that the racket never stops so while
you're doing this exercise you
and also do a little technical thing
here and that is you're always swinging
your racket on the edge so this is the
edges exercise that I also demonstrated
in one of my previous videos so as
you're doing this exercise you always
lead with the edge so when I swing this
way I lead with this edge and then I'm
doing my back swing I'm coming from the
trophy position into the drop I'm
leading with this edge then I rotate my
shoulders a little bit now I lead with
this edge then I do this transition from
this edge to this edge and then I go
into the follow-through then I go out
and I repeat the whole process again so
see if you can notice now that all the
time as I'm swinging except at the
context point where my racquet points
towards the camera or towards you all
the time the racket is on the edge and
so that's a very good exercise to
reinforce the proper technique the
proper movement of the racket in the end
I'd like to point out that I use these
serving progressions these fundamentals
almost daily when I work with tennis
players on their serve so make sure that
you can execute them properly that
you're doing them correctly before you
start adding more advanced stuff like
really coiling your body working on your
kick serve jumping into the court or
something like that thanks for watching
and let me know how these seven steps to
a proper advance serve work for you